（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)
（徽标弹出）
(logo popping)
（金属滑动）
(metal sliding)
- 在本视频中，我们将介绍如何设置
- In this video, we take a look at setting up
用于训练的自定义损失函数。
a custom loss function for training.
在默认损失函数中，所有样本，
In the default loss function, all samples,
例如这些代码片段，都被同等对待
such as these code snippets, are treated the same
不管他们的内容如何，但有一些场景
irrespective of their content but there are scenarios
对样本进行不同加权可能有意义。
where it could make sense to weight the samples differently.
例如，如果一个样本包含很多标记
If, for example, one sample contains a lot of tokens
我们感兴趣的
that are of interest to us
或者样本是否具有有利的标记多样性。
or if a sample has a favorable diversity of tokens.
我们还可以实施其他启发式
We can also implement other heuristics
与模式匹配或其他规则。
with pattern matching or other rules.
对于每个样本，我们在训练过程中得到一个损失值
For each sample, we get a loss value during training
我们可以将损失与重量结合起来。
and we can combine that loss with a weight.
然后我们可以创建一个加权和
Then we can create a weighted sum
或对所有样本取平均值
or average over all samples
获得该批次的最终损失。
to get the final loss for the batch.
让我们看一个具体的例子。
Let's have a look at a specific example.
我们要建立一个语言模型
We want to set up a language model
这有助于我们自动完成常见的数据科学代码。
that helps us autocomplete common data science code.
对于那个任务，我们想给样本赋予更强的权重
For that task, we would like to weight samples stronger
其中与数据科学堆栈相关的令牌，
where tokens related to the data science stack,
如 pd 或 np，出现的频率更高。
such as pd or np, occur more frequently.
在这里你看到一个损失函数正是这样做的
Here you see a loss function that does exactly that
用于因果语言建模。
for causal language modeling.
它采用模型的输入和预测的逻辑，
It takes the model's input and predicted logits,
以及作为输入的密钥标记。
as well as the key tokens, as input.
首先，输入和逻辑对齐。
First, the inputs and logits are aligned.
然后计算每个样本的损失，
Then the loss per sample is calculated,
其次是重量。
followed by the weights.
最后，将损失和权重合并并返回。
Finally, the loss and the weights are combined and returned.
这是一个相当大的函数，让我们仔细看看
This is a pretty big function, so let's take a closer look
在损失和重量块。
at the loss and the weight blocks.
在计算标准损失时，
During the calculation of the standard loss,
logits 和标签在批次上变平。
the logits and labels are flattened over the batch.
有了视图，我们展开张量得到矩阵
With the view, we unflatten the tensor to get the matrix
批次中的每个样本都有一行和一列
with a row for each sample in the batch and a column
对于样本序列中的每个位置。
for each position in the sequence of the sample.
我们不需要每个头寸的损失，
We don't need the loss per position,
所以我们对每个样本的所有头寸的损失进行平均。
so we average the loss over all positions for each sample.
对于权重，我们使用布尔逻辑得到一个张量
For the weights, we use Boolean logic to get a tensor
出现关键字的位置为 1，未出现的位置为 0。
with 1s where a keyword occurred and 0s where not.
这个张量有一个额外的维度
This tensor has an additional dimension
作为我们刚刚看到的损失张量，因为我们得到
as the loss tensor we just saw because we get
单独矩阵中每个关键字的信息。
the information for each keyword in a separate matrix.
我们只想知道
We only want to know
每个样本出现多少次关键字，
how many times keywords occurred per sample,
因此我们可以对每个样本的总体关键字和所有位置求和。
so we can sum overall keywords and all positions per sample.
现在我们快到了。
Now we're almost there.
我们只需要将损失与每个样本的权重结合起来。
We only need to combine the loss with the weight per sample.
我们用元素明智的乘法来做到这一点
We do this with element wise multiplication
然后对批次中的总体样本进行平均。
and then average overall samples in the batch.
到底，
In the end,
我们对整批只有一个损失值
we have exactly one loss value for the whole batch
这是整个必要的逻辑
and this is the whole necessary logic
创建自定义加权损失。
to create a custom weighted loss.
让我们看看如何利用自定义损失
Let's see how we can make use of that custom loss
与 Accelerate 和 Trainer 一起。
with Accelerate and the Trainer.
在 Accelerate 中，我们只传递 input_ids
In Accelerate, we just pass the input_ids
到模型以获得 logits
to the model to get the logits
然后我们可以调用自定义损失函数。
and then we can call the custom loss function.
之后，我们继续正常的训练循环
After that, we continue with the normal training loop
例如，向后调用。
by, for example, calling backward.
对于 Trainer，我们可以覆盖
For the Trainer, we can overwrite
标准训练器的计算损失函数。
the compute loss function of the standard trainer.
我们只需要确保我们返回
We just need to make sure that we return
损失和模型以相同的格式输出。
the loss and the model outputs in the same format.
这样，您就可以集成自己的出色损失函数
With that, you can integrate your own awesome loss function
与培训师和加速。
with both the Trainer and Accelerate.
（空气呼啸）
(air whooshing)